# Cleyton Fábio

e-mail: cleyton.flb@gmail.com phone: +55(74)933005604

linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/iamcflb/

github: https://github.com/cflb/ gitlab: https://gitlab.com/pixi3s

Information Systems Analyst (Dev | **SysAdmin** | **Security** | **Software** engineer |

Linuxer)

### **Abstract**

I am constantly encouraged to solve problems with GNU/Linux, or with some free or open source technology. In the last 22 years i could collaborate with several companies and government, accumulating a large experience as SysAdmin, NetworkAdmin, Infrastructure, Developer, Teacher, Software Engineer.

#### Some services under control:

- web apache, nginx, lighthttpd, toncat
- Databases MySQL, PostgreSQl, SQLite, Oracle, NoSQL.
- ServiceApplication drupal, wordpress, odoo, joonla
- Network (Architecture, tunneling (VPN), Protocols, Sec, Monitoring)
- Containerization docker and docker-compose, podman, jail
- Virtualization libvirt, kvm, vmware, vbox openvz, vserver.
- Sec and Monitoring Shellscript, Firewalling, exploiting, iptables, proxy/squid, netstat, tcpdump, sed, nagios, grailog.

### **Software Engineering:**

- Agile methods (XP, Scrun, Kaban), development team management, software design patterns, data modeling (ORM - Object Relational Mapper), UML, Distributed systems.
- Python: automation scripts, crawlers, ETLs, Web Dev/APIs (Django, Django Rest Framework, Flask)
- GIT Flow/GitHub/GitLab + CI/CD)
- *Infrastructure as Code* (TerraForm, ansible, testinfra with molecule)
- Unix-based Operating Systems
- Containerization with docker + docker-compose
- Vagrant + LibVirt

#### **AWS Cloud:**

 AWS Beanstalk, EC2, RDS, LB (Classic, Application and Network), CodeCommit, CodePipeline, S3

### Teaching, Research and Extension

In the last 15 years I have also worked as a professor at higher and technical education institutions (UFRPE, FIS, ITEP, IFBAIANO).

### **Last Project:**

In 2020 I led a team to develop the ROP-E platform, a strategic platform for managing and controlling police incidents for the State of Bahia (https://www.rop-e.com).

## Experiência

Bahia Federal Institute of Education, Science and Technology Substitute teacher 2019 - October 2020 (1 year) Guanambi/BA, Brazil

Tag.i .. Creative Intelligence on the Web CEO January 2010 - january 2018 (8 yeas 1 month) Serra Talhada/PE, Brazil Consultancy **and** specialized, **int**elligent **and** creative solutions **for** web **and** mobile.

UFRPE - Rural Federal University of Pernambuco Substitute teacher September 2014 - September 2016 (2 years 1 month)

Free **Server Network** 

Voluntary

2006 - January 2015 (9 years)

The Free PE **Network** is a horizontal action promoted with the common objective **to** help people. The **network** provides web services!

Pernambuco Institute of Technology - ITEP
teacher/tutor
October 2006 - November 2012 (6 years 2 months)
Serra Talhada, Pernambuco, Brazil
- Technology consultant **for** innovative projects
- teacher of technical courses on Internet Software Development

Ministry of Communications of Brazil GESAC Implementer February 2004 - April 2006 (2 years 3 months) Pernambuco, Paraiba, Sergipe, Alagoas, Brasilia / Brazil Social Implementer of the GESAC Program - Electronic Government **Service** of Citizen **Service** 

Performed the following activities:

- Facilities of Community Laboratories and Telecentres
- Administration and Maintenance of the program's community servers

of Digital Inclusion Brazil (IDBrasil)

- Operations with audio/video stream services
- Trainings

SESI - Industry Social **Service**Systems **and Network** Manager
January 2001 - January 2004 (3 years 1 month)
Petrolina, Pernambuco, Brazil

- Managed the Computer **Network**
- Network Equipment (ethernet/wifi/VPM)
- Servers, Data, Authentication, Cache, Printing among others.

### **Academic education**

#### **UNITER**

International University Center
MBA, Software Engineering for Mobile Devices (2019 - 2020)

#### **UFRPE**

Federal Rural University of Pernambuco - UFRPE Information Systems (2006 - 2012)